urologychannel.com 2011-06-05

# Privacy Statement - Remedy Health Media and Healthcommunities.com - Healthcommunities.com, Inc.

## Remedy Health Media Privacy Policy

We have created this privacy policy (hereinafter, this "Privacy Policy") in order to disclose how Remedy Health Media gathers, uses, disseminates, and safeguards the information that we collect from you on this Website as well as through the reader service information we collect in the magazines we publish. We understand the importance that consumers place on privacy and have designed our service with this in mind. By using this Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

A third party from which you receive goods or services through the Website may maintain a separate privacy policy that governs the collection and use of your information as it relates to their provision of goods or services to you.

The Website and all Additional Services (as defined below) are designed and targeted to audiences and governed by and operated in accordance with the laws, regulations, and treaties of the United States of America. We make no representation that the Website is operated in accordance with or governed by the laws of other nations or jurisdictions. If you are located in the European Union or elsewhere outside of the United States of America and you use or attempt to use the Website, you do so at your own risk and you are responsible for compliance with any applicable local, national laws rules and regulations and, if applicable, international treaties.

## Anti-Spam

Remedy Health Media Websites comply with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 and include the following:

## Your California Privacy Rights

California law allows users of this Website that reside in California to know the third parties with whom we shared their Personal Information (defined below) for those parties' own direct marketing purposes. The type of information and instances in which we share such information is detailed in this Privacy Policy. However, if you are a resident of California and you would like to know the specific companies with whom we shared your Personal Information for their own direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the categories of the information we shared, you should please feel free to send us an e-mail at [privacy@remedylife.com]. Alternatively, you may send us a written request for such information to the following address:  
Remedy Health Media  
500 Fifth Avenue, Suite 1900  
New York, NY 10110  
Attention: Privacy (California Privacy Rights)

## Personal Information Remedy Health Media Collects From You

If you are receiving Remedy Health Media publications and promotional messages via postal or e-mail, this is due to your having registered to receive such messages online or to your having returned a business reply card to Remedy Health Media upon which you included certain Personal Information and indicated your interest in receiving such communications. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Personal Information" shall mean information that can be used to identify you, including, but not limited to: (a) a first and last name; (b) a home or other physical address, including street name and name of city or town; (c) an e-mail address; (d) a telephone number; (e) age/birth date; or (f) personal health information. Remedy Health Media collects Personal Information from you through online registration, business reply cards and online surveys and questionnaires that you submit. 

This Website makes forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users (collectively, "Additional Services"). Please remember that any information that you may post in these Additional Services becomes public information when you post it and the use thereof is not within our control. Please exercise caution and discretion when posting Personal Information in these Additional Services.

A user may be required to submit his/her name and e-mail address to post a question in the Additional Services. This information is not used by Remedy Health Media, unless the user registers for an Additional Service, in which case the Personal Information submitted shall be retained in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Passwords are retained only when a user registers for an Additional Service. Each Additional Service may have additional terms applicable to the use thereof ("Additional Terms") and by registering for or participating in such service, you agree to be bound by such Additional Terms.

All users of the Website are required to provide true, current, complete and accurate Personal Information when prompted and we have the right to refuse or revoke your right to use our Website and/or reject and delete any entry you make, if we have reason to believe information you provide to us is or may be false, fraudulent, or inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

A user may update his/her Personal Information by submitting a request via the contact information provided below in the Section entitled **Contacting us about privacy questions or concerns**. We attempt to reply promptly to these requests and may, in our discretion, file comments submitted to improve the Website and any Additional Services, or review and discard the information. 

## How Remedy Health Media Uses Personal Information

Remedy Health Media may use your Personal Information to send postal and/or e-mail communications to you, including communications sent on behalf of its advertisers and other partners. If you indicated your interest in receiving health or medical information from third parties, then Remedy Health Media may share your Personal Information with such third parties. Remedy Health Media does not share your Personal Information with any third parties other than as specifically stated in this Privacy Policy. Remedy Health Media may use your Personal Information for internal business purposes, such as performing market analysis and analyzing and managing its business.

Remedy Health Media may provide subscriber subscriber information in aggregate, de-identified form (i.e., in a manner that the data cannot be traced back to you) to its advertisers and other parties. Remedy Health Media at times may share Personal Information (name and physical address) with third parties for marketing and fundraising purposes.

Remedy Health Media may, in its sole discretion, share or transfer your Personal Information where permitted or required by law, to comply with legal process (for example, Remedy Health Media may disclose your information as necessary to comply with an authorized civil, criminal or regulatory investigation), to protect the security or integrity of its databases or the Website, to protect Remedy Health Media's business or reputation, to take precautions against legal liability, in the event of a business transition (see below), to protect and defend the rights or property of Remedy Health Media, for required institutional risk control, or for resolving disputes, inquiries or complaints with respect to your use of the Website.

Remedy Health Media may also employ other companies and individuals to perform certain functions on its behalf. Examples include sending direct and electronic mail, information technology support, maintaining and removing duplicate information from user lists, analyzing data and providing marketing analysis. The agents performing these limited functions on Remedy Health Media's behalf shall have access to its users’ Personal Information as needed to perform their functions for Remedy Health Media but are not permitted to use your Personal Information for other purposes. All Remedy Health Media contractors operate under federal and state laws regarding consumer privacy.

## Business Transitions

In the event Remedy Health Media goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your Personal Information might be among the assets transferred.

## Your IP Address

Each time you visit [www.remedyhealthmedia.com](http://www.remedyhealthmedia.com/) (the "Website"), our web server automatically recognizes your IP address and the web page from which you came. Your IP address may be used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information about you. We also may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers, to administer the Website and to better serve you in using the Website.

## Cookies and Action Tags

The first time a user provides an e-mail address in connection with their activities at the Website, Remedy Health Media assigns an identification number to that e-mail address and deploys a cookie to the applicable user's PC. Whenever that user comes back to the Website using the same PC, the cookie allows the Website to identify the user and to recall the user's e-mail address. If, at any time, a user provides other information in connection with their activities on the Website (such as name, address, birth date, gender, etc.), Remedy Health Media may store that information, along with the user's e-mail address, in its user database. Remedy Health Media may use the Personal Information stored in its database: (i) to effectuate the purpose or transaction for which the information was originally provided by a user; (ii) to pre-populate information fields in the event a user wishes to purchase products and/or services or sign up for and/or subscribe to services, promotions or other offers in the future; (iii) to ensure that a user will not be repeatedly exposed to the same advertisements, offers and/or promotions while visiting the Website; and/or (iv) to, in connection with regular communication with a user, include offers, promotions or advertisements that were historically, or are likely to be, of interest to that user. Remedy Health Media also may use cookies to anonymously track and target the interests of our users to further enhance the experience on the Website. To find out more about cookies, please visit www.cookiecentral.com.

Action Tags, Web Beacons and other Data Collection Methods: An action tag or a web-beacon (also known as a clear gif or a pixel tag) is a method used to track responses or actions by visitors who view certain advertisements or other information on a website. Action tags are 1x1 pixel images embedded in a website page that are used to transparently collect information. Remedy Health Media may use action tags to count the number of times that visitors click on a particular banner ad or visit the pages of our Website and to provide information about what products are viewed or purchased. Remedy Health Media reserves the right to retain this cookie and action tag data indefinitely. Remedy Health Media at times links the data collected through the means described in this paragraph with your Personal Information for purposes of customizing messages to you and customizing Website content for you. At no time will Remedy Health Media share cookie-related, action-tag-related and/or generated information and/or data with third parties.

## Security Precautions

Remedy Health Media strives to protect the privacy and security of the data it collects and maintains. Remedy Health Media (including through its contractors) maintains reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards and security measures to protect the confidentiality, loss, misuse, and alteration of your Personal Information. Remedy Health Media keeps your Personal Information only for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or to comply with any applicable legal or ethical reporting or document retention requirements. We have taken certain physical, electronic, contractual and managerial steps to safeguard and secure the information we collect from Website visitors and magazine readers. Please note, however, that it is your responsibility to maintain the confidentiality of your password associated with this Website, if any. 

## Other Websites

Remedy Health Media undertakes the effort to see that any third party to which we disclose Personal Information is under a contractual obligation to us to use the Personal Information solely for the purposes for which the information was disclosed.

This Website may contain links to other third-party owned and/or operated websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third-party websites. In some cases, you may be able to make a purchase though one of these third-party websites. In these instances, you may be required to provide certain information, such as a credit card number, to register or complete a transaction at such website. These third-party websites have separate privacy and data collection practices and we have no responsibility or liability relating to such policies or practices.

## Minors

Visitors under 18 years of age are not permitted to use and/or submit their Personal Information at the Website. We do not knowingly solicit or collect information from visitors under the age of 18. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate and monitor the interactive activities of their children. We will not be liable for any content or advertisements viewed by minor children in violation of the terms of this Privacy Policy.

## Removal of Your Information/Opting Out

At your request, Remedy Health Media will remove Personal Information that you have provided to us. You may do so by e-mailing privacy@Remedylife.com.

Remedy Health Media provides users the option to opt-out from receiving electronic mailings, including electronic mailings sent by Remedy Health Media on behalf of third party advertisers. Users may unsubscribe from receiving e-mails at any time by following the instructions contained at the end of every e-mail. Note that where Remedy Health Media has provided your Personal Information to third parties, Remedy Health Media cannot control the use of that information by such third parties. 

You might continue to receive e-mails from Remedy Health Media for up to ten (10) days following your unsubscribing. If, after that point, a user is still receiving e-mail from Remedy Health Media, the user should contact Remedy Health Media at emailadministrator@remedyhealthmedia.com.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Remedy Health Media reserves the right, at its discretion, to change, modify, add and/or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time. All Privacy Policy changes will take effect immediately upon their posting on the Website. Please check this page periodically for changes. Your continued acceptance of Remedy Health Media's promotional e-mails following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy shall indicate that you accept these changes and agree to continue receiving e-mails from Remedy Health Media notwithstanding the changes. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please unsubscribe to Remedy Health Media s promotional e-mails by following the instructions contained at the end of every e-mail.

## Contacting us about privacy questions or concerns

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please e-mail us at privacy@remedyhealthmedia.com, or send a letter to Remedy Health Media, 500 Fifth Avenue, Suite 1900, New York, NY 10110.

## Sole Statement

The foregoing statements, terms and conditions contained in this Privacy Policy is the sole statement of our privacy policy, and no summary, restatement or other version, or other statement or policy, in any form, including, without limitation, machine-generated, is valid. 

This Privacy Policy was last modified on September 29, 2009 and is effective immediately.  
© Copyright 2010 Remedy Health Media. All Rights Reserved.

Physician-developed and -monitored.  
Original Date of Publication:   
Reviewed by:   
Last Reviewed:   
Last Modified:25 Oct 2010 

© 1998-2011 Healthcommunities.com, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
